A while ago I made a video
The topic was
Why you should start
Vibe Coding immediately
At the end, I introduced my new startup project
An AI community
As a result, this video became my most controversial one since I started YouTube.
one of the most controversial.
I received a lot of negative comments
So much so that some fans sent me private messages to express their support.
caring about my mental state
I hope I won't be hurt by these comments.
When I saw these private messages
My first reaction was of course very touched.
Thank you for your concern.
My second reaction was
I found it very interesting.
Just as I replied to them
Actually, don't worry.
I was not affected.
Because what you see
It's just some noise.
And the signals I see and the comment section
The feeling it gives people is just the opposite.
The contrast between them
made me realize an interesting and important question
That is, if we can't
If we separate noise from signal,
It's very likely to be misled by noise
Make wrong judgments and decisions
and even go down the wrong path.
Especially in today's information explosion era
Having your own signal filter is crucial.
So I think I should make a video
to combine this startup with some of my life experiences
Share with everyone
5 mental models that help me distinguish between signals and noise in life
I hope it can bring some inspiration to everyone.
The first mental model that helps me distinguish between noise and signal is
Always remember the 1% rule in a crowd.
This so-called 1% rule
It says that in a community on the Internet
or among the entire audience
90% of people are lurkers
The silent majority
They just browse passively
Only 10% of people may interact
And among them, only 1% of people
contributed most of the interactive content.
This means that very few people
often have a disproportionate impact.
So you have to realize
What you see on the surface is not equal to the truth.
So those comments in my YouTube comment section
often come from this 1% of people.
And more importantly,
On the internet, negative emotions spread more strongly.
It's like when you go to a restaurant's Google review to see
If someone thinks it's good
He probably won't leave a comment.
But if the experience is not good
Anger will motivate people to be more willing to make negative comments.
In fact, our entire internet is now full of negative emotions.
These emotions are very easily passed through this 1% of people.
showcased in a concentrated way.
This will make you feel that the world is very bad.
Bad news everywhere
Every time I go back to my country, I get asked
Is Canada still safe?
If you can't make it, just come back home.
At this point you will find
Originally living in Canada
and the Canada that others see in the news
are two different worlds.
Actually, the truth is
This 1% of voices are disproportionately amplified.
People think what they see is a signal
But what you actually get may be noise.
But just knowing that what you see is not necessarily the truth
is far from enough.
He can only tell you that this may be noise.
But what are the real signals?
First of all, I think you should try to get
The data of the 90% silent majority.
Let's talk about my video.
Although the comment section may be full of scolding
But the backend data shows
The approval rate is nearly 94%.
And this video also gained me nearly 3,000 followers.
So these data representing the silent majority
formed a huge contrast with the emotions in the comment section.
This is why
My physical feeling is very different from the audience who cares about me.
But for me,
These data are still not the most accurate signals.
I want to find more core and direct information.
We need to introduce my second mental model.
That is, transactions are often the most real signals.
The so-called transaction is to vote with money.
Because verbal support and opposition are very easy.
But only when people are willing to pay the actual cost
The signal they convey is the most real.
Then I would like to share a little story about the new community this time.
I was actually very nervous after the video was released.
I'm eager to know the clearest signal.
That is, how many people will pay to join this community.
As you all know, I have my own book club community.
A mouthful of new rice
It went online more than two years ago.
That was very interesting at the time.
The announcement video was less than 6 minutes long.
Someone had already joined 30 seconds after it went live.
The video is not over yet.
Dozens of people have already paid to become founding members.
But this time it's a little different.
This video is over 20 minutes long.
I didn't mention this new community until the very end.
Of course I was thinking
When will the first person to pay appear?
As soon as the video was released, I started playing it simultaneously.
staring at the screen nervously
No one came in for 5 minutes.
No one came in for 10 minutes.
Still no one came in after 15 minutes.
I was a little self-doubting at the time.
Did I screw this up?
Interestingly, at the exact moment the video ended
The first person came in.
Then my phone kept sending reminders.
The second, the third, the tenth, the hundredth.
Online for 72 hours
We have over 700 paying members.
Nearly 1,400 after three weeks.
This is for me and my co-creation partners.
is the most accurate signal.
We know that at least we didn't screw this up.
So why do I value transaction data so much?
and ignore those negative comments?
This is what my years of entrepreneurial and life experience have taught me.
That is, when possible,
I should try to get signals through transactions as much as possible.
This is because in a normally functioning society
Money is a very direct and accurate signal.
If you put in a lot of effort
You think you're going in the right direction.
But no one pays for the product or service you launch.
Then this could be an important signal.
You might be doing something wrong somewhere.
A while ago I was chatting with members of the community.
We talked about making YouTube videos.
I said the biggest mistake I made on YouTube was
is not being able to commercialize it sooner.
When I first started on YouTube
I'm purely passionate, just sharing.
But there's a problem here.
My passion, my self-perceived value
These things can't give me an accurate signal.
It wasn't until later that I realized a sentence.
That is, only things that make money have vitality.
I'm not encouraging profit-seeking here.
What I want to say is
Even if you are doing the most selfless and sincere sharing
If it doesn't make money
Then this matter may not be sustainable.
If I don't consider monetization
I can't even cover the filming costs.
I'm losing money.
This will make things very difficult.
More importantly,
If there is no transaction
You can't even get an accurate signal.
This will leave you in deep confusion.
Can't find the right direction.
And the mistake I made for a long time was
I didn't even give others a chance.
Let others help me monetize.
I call this disease "performing without getting paid".
So what does that mean?
You've all seen street performers, right?
When they are performing
They often put their hats or rice bowls on the ground.
Let everyone give some money.
It has a behavior that promotes transactions.
But what I observed is
Many of our YouTubers don't do this.
We put a lot of effort into showing off our skills.
But never put the hat on the ground.
What we do is more like
You're performing on the street.
I hope the fruit stand owner next to me sells his fruit and then
give you some money.
But the fruit stand owner makes money by selling his own products.
That's a signal to him.
Not a signal to you.
For a long time
I'm the one who performs without putting his hat on the ground.
So the advice I want to give to everyone who wants to be a YouTuber is
Before you make your first video
You have to think clearly
Where is my rice bowl?
Do I have a hat that I can put on the ground?
In the process of monetizing my YouTube channel
Besides having your own products
My hat
Getting sponsorship is also a very important part.
And in my interactions with them
also deeply confirms
A transaction is a signal.
The pressure of making a sponsored video is actually quite high.
Because you want to prove your worth.
So we often focus on the number of views.
I had a very interesting experience once.
A sponsor sponsored one of my videos.
As a result, the number of views was very poor.
I was a little disappointed in myself at the time.
Even a little ashamed.
I thought they would definitely not come to me again in the future.
But I didn't expect that a week after the video was released
This sponsor came to me for cooperation again.
And also asked to sign a few more contracts.
This is the signal.
This video looks bad in my eyes.
But the sponsor is still willing to find me again, which shows that
The data he saw was of very high quality.
This gave me a lot of confidence.
Let me know where my business value is.
Speaking of sponsors
I must thank the channel's long-term sponsor here.
Interactive Brokers
I have been cooperating with IB for more than two years.
Such a long period of cooperation
They gave me great creative freedom and support.
This is also a very valuable and real signal for me.
For me,
IB is not just a partner of the channel.
It is also the brokerage I use for my personal investments.
It is precisely because I used their services that a transaction occurred.
and thus generated trust.
Then I was willing to cooperate with them.
to recommend their products.
This is a way to build trust through transactions.
Then a virtuous cycle of supply.
So if you are interested in investing
I strongly recommend everyone to use IB.
You can check the link in our description.
Your clicks will benefit me.
This is also a form of support for me.
Okay, now let's talk about trading.
I know a lot of people are afraid to trade.
This may be precisely because we know
Trading will give us the most direct and real signal.
So we dare not face this truth.
Because we are afraid of failure.
But whether you dare or not
The truth is there.
The sooner you know the truth, the more important it is to you.
Because when you don't have this signal
You are actually living in a state of self-paralysis.
even in a more painful and confused state.
It's like when I wasn't seriously doing business monetization.
I had doubts about myself for a long time.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Can I keep going?
But when the Yikou XinFan community went online
Someone came in at the 30th second.
After two years
There are still many original partners who are still active.
I know, OK.
My stuff has value in the hearts of the audience.
He is willing to vote for me.
This gave me confidence.
Let me be my true self.
Say what I want to say.
Including even making this video.
It's also me and a friend from the community.
We talked about it during our coffee chat.
I said this video of mine might be a bit controversial again.
He said it's okay, Ray.
It's okay for you to be yourself.
This is what we really want to see.
And so you have the video you're watching now.
OK
We use the 1% rule to question noise.
Get real signals through trading.
But even the most realistic transaction data
may also fluctuate in the short term.
bring misleading.
So my third mental model is
Signals come more from long-term trends.
rather than short-term fluctuations.
We often say in investing
You should focus on long-term trends.
I've shared this before.
An author I really like, Taleb, said in his book
Mathematically, you can actually prove that
In investing, when you set the observation range
When it becomes extremely short
The signal-to-noise ratio is reduced.
The proportion of noise will become much larger.
Besides investment
In entrepreneurship and life
This rule also holds true.
Let's take my new community as an example.
The number of people who came in the first three days of launch was very exaggerated.
All the teachers were very excited.
But then the speed slowed down.
After a price increase
The speed of joining has dropped significantly.
The teachers began to worry.
But I told everyone
You don't have to worry.
Because the data from the first three days
and the decline after the price adjustment.
are short-term fluctuations.
It can be said to be noise.
We may need to wait until three months
Even after half a year
to see a real pattern.
This is because every time we start a new business
Because of the novelty
We are easily attracted by temporary data.
Today's sales are very high.
It's easy to create a linear misunderstanding.
Assuming it will be like this every day in the future.
Then one day the data drops.
It feels like the end of the world is coming.
This is because you are focusing on a specific point in time.
What you observe is more noise.
What you really need to do is to look at it over a long period of time.
Observe a long-term trend.
Long enough time
Only then can you observe the pattern.
The reason why I'm not panicking is
It's because I've experienced so much of this.
Experience from zero to one.
My experience is
Don't be nervous.
Don't panic because of temporary gains and losses.
We should trust the process.
Let the bullets fly for a while.
Actually, life is like this too.
There are many important signals in life.
all need to be obtained through long-term investment.
And we have two perspectives to lengthen the dimension.
One is to look back at the past.
Look at yourself last year or even five years ago.
and yourself now.
What is the overall trend?
Are you always changing?
always getting better.
If so,
That means you are on the right track.
The other is to look forward.
Be a time traveler.
Imagine yourself a year from now, five years from now.
The decisions you make now
What kind of impact will you have at that time?
Through this kind of time travel
Put yourself in the future.
Look back at today from a reverse perspective.
can provide you with very important signals.
OK, the first three models are more about
About how to interpret signals from the outside world.
But eventually these signals
needs to be filtered and judged by yourself.
This requires the introduction of an inward-looking signal filtering model.
A couple of days ago, I received a book I shared before.
A letter from Paul, the author of Pathless Path.
He said his traditional Chinese version is already on the market in Taiwan.
The simplified Chinese version will also be published soon.
He wants to send me a few of his signed books.
Because he found that many Chinese readers told him
are all through my videos.
I know about his book.
This is a little thank you from him.
But what I want to say is
I'm the one who really needs to be thanked.
Because through conversation with him
I have benefited a lot.
I learned a very important point.
That is your energy.
is a crucial signal filter in life.
For example, if you are facing a new opportunity,
I feel that it is giving you more energy.
Just like he said in the book
If you feel that
Hell yeah
Then this is a correct signal.
If you find yourself facing something
It's draining your energy.
Your whole body is resisting.
Then this is a signal to tell you
Maybe you shouldn't do this.
It's been over a year since I visited Paul.
In this year
Especially after I went through a health crisis
Using energy as a signal
has become a principle I practice every day.
And in this year
I have a new understanding of it.
If using energy as a signal is
Listen to your body
Then the fifth model
Following your intuition is
Listen to your heart
It can even be said that
Listen to the universe
We read a book in our community called
Don't believe everything you think
Its core point is
Don't overthink it.
You have to follow your intuition.
What does that mean?
Many of our important ideas and intuitions
are because of overthinking
let it disappear without becoming a reality.
It says in this book
Overthinking is not normal thinking.
It is more brought about by our human instinct of fear.
In our long-term evolution
have an instinctual fear of failure.
Because in the long primitive period
The consequence of failure is often death.
So we will over-judge
Try every means to avoid failure.
So this leads to when we have an intuition
We will think of all kinds of possibilities of failure.
The obstacles we may encounter
The preparations that may need to be made
This often leads to many of our ideas
not put into practice.
Because staying put is the safest thing to do.
But we often overlook that in modern society
The consequences of failure for many ideas and opportunities are very low.
But the potential upside is very high.
So although overthinking stems from our survival instinct
But in modern society
It often suppresses our true intuition.
generate internal noise.
And the one that initially made you feel energetic
The intuition that excites you
may be the real signal.
This reminds me of the book The Creative Act.
It mentions that your thoughts are actually given to you by the universe.
When you have an idea
As a creator
You are obliged to pass it on.
Yes, what you are doing is not creating.
but to deliver.
Turn this idea from the universe into reality.
If you overthink it
Hesitated and didn't do this.
And someone else did it.
You might think someone stole your idea.
But in fact, you have not fulfilled your responsibility as a creator.
Bring this idea to the world.
So it found another carrier.
came to this world.
Looking back at my AI community
It's probably the fastest startup project in my life.
From idea to execution, it only took two weeks.
I was thinking at the time
With such a community
It's definitely helpful to people.
And this is exactly where my passion lies.
So I did what I said I would do.
If I had thought about it then
What if people judge me and I fail?
What if no one signs up?
Maybe I haven't even started yet.
Then I might not have gotten the precious signals I have now.
drowned in noise.
True failure is not failure after trying.
but you didn't even try.
Trapped by overthinking
When someone else does what you want to do but don't dare to do
You feel offended.
I feel that others are not worthy.
But this is your problem.
Because you didn't listen to your intuition and energy.
These two very valuable signals.
You have not fulfilled your responsibility as a creator.
Pass on the signal from the universe and make it a reality.
Finally, I want to share
The book we read in September
A quote from The Lean Learning
The richest place in the world is the cemetery.
Because there are countless novel ideas buried there that were never realized.
These buried ideas, in my opinion,
It's not just a lack of courage.
More likely,
They don't know what the real signals and noises of life are.
They are disturbed by external comments.
Confused by short-term fluctuations
and hindered by their own inner fear and overthinking.
In the end, I failed to follow my true energy and intuition to act.
to get the signals of life.
Walk your own path.
I hope the five models shared today can help you.
Thanks for watching.